{
    "id": "bdb0cbe186844056b93ff45c7b1a026f",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Pakistan successfully ……………….. its nuclear capable radar dodging cruise missile on July",
            "description": "When there is a definite past time reference, we use the simple past.",
            "answers": [
                "test fired",
                "has test fired",
                "had test fired"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Australia …………….. 40% of the world’s known uranium reserves.",
            "description": "We use the simple present tense to talk about facts and general truths.",
            "answers": [
                "hold",
                "holds",
                "has held",
                "is holding"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Union cabinet ………….. the landmark civilian nuclear co-operation agreement with the USA in March.",
            "description": "We use the simple past tense when there is a definite past time reference.",
            "answers": [
                "has approved",
                "is approving",
                "approved"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "A group of students ................. an environmentally friendly Eco One race car.",
            "description": "The present perfect is the most common tense for giving news. ",
            "answers": [
                "built",
                "have built",
                "had built",
                "build"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A powerful earthquake ........................... Japan on July 16 killing and injuring several people.",
            "description": "When there is a definite reference to the past, we use the simple past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "hits",
                "hit",
                "has hit",
                "had hit"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "After analyzing thousands of skulls British scientists .......................... at the conclusion that modern humans ...................... from a single point in Africa.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "have arrived, originated",
                "have arrived, have originated",
                "are arriving, have originated"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Scientists think they .............................. the energy source of the spectacular colour displays seen in the Northern Lights.",
            "description": "We use the present perfect to give news. ",
            "answers": [
                "discovered",
                "have discovered",
                "had discovered"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The world’s oceans which ...................... about a third of the carbon dioxide emitted from burning fossil fuels ...................... more acidic.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about ongoing actions and situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "are absorbing, are becoming",
                "absorb, are becoming",
                "absorb, had become"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Babylonians were the first to make New Year resolutions and people all over the world ......................... them ever since.",
            "description": "The present perfect and the present perfect continuous tenses are more common with the time expressions since and for.",
            "answers": [
                "are breaking",
                "broke",
                "have been breaking"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "During his childhood days, he .................... barefoot deep into the forest to collect firewood.",
            "description": "We use would + infinitive to talk about past habits. ",
            "answers": [
                "have trudged",
                "will trudge",
                "would trudge"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The world’s oldest city ................... in the deserts of Peru, or so believes a group of archaeologists.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is existing",
                "existed",
                "has existed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The castle ........................ on the hill for 500 years.",
            "description": "The present perfect and the present perfect continuous tenses can both be used to talk about situations that started in the past and have continued up to the present.",
            "answers": [
                "is standing",
                "has stood",
                "has been standing"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}